<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<news-item id="WBMA-95ZS-KU0O-LXFH"><date>2014-03-20</date><title>Our banks not without fault</title><source>thestar.com</source><author/><text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Re: Meltdown's costs: $12.6 trillion; Top CEOs convicted: 0, March 15 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meltdown's costs: $12.6 trillion; Top CEOs convicted: 0, March 15 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Olive seems to have ingested too much of the Kool-Aid provided by the small but oh-so-comfy Canadian financial community when he writes "every major economy save Canada had to bail out its banking systems." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;i&gt;Thieves of Bay Street&lt;/i&gt;, Bruce Livesey reminds us that the federal government "created a unique program that allowed [Canadian] banks to move between $69 billions and $125 billions of mortgage assets off their balance sheets. As in the U.S. examples cited by Olive, it is not clear that our vaunted Canadian banks lent out any of these rescue dollars intended to ensure the banks' liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, Livesey describes the ethical boundary-skirting roles our banks played in the marketing of corporate hot air balloons such as Enron and Global Crossing.
In every case, as in those American examples Olive cites, our bankers took home large bonuses even as the banks suffered massive write-downs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like Mr. Olive, we all need to view our banks without the rose-coloured glasses they've been encouraging us to wear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ab Dukacz&lt;/b&gt;, Mississauga&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Olive's excellent column on the U.S. financial sector should be on the front page of every newspaper. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although he speaks about the U.S. economy it certainly bears out the adage that when the U.S. elephant sneezes we catch cold. And we too have many stories of the failure of the justice system in Canada - Bre-X anyone?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the same U.S. that proposes to bring good government to many emerging countries. It also decries the graft and corruption in these countries. How hypocritical! No wonder we and they are totally cynical regarding the fairness in our systems and have little confidence in our governments. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stella Watson&lt;/b&gt;, Toronto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe as a sign of good faith to taxpayers, the U.S. could extend the statute of limitations to possible prosecutions of Wall St. bankers and government enablers responsible for the destruction of U.S. lives from five years to 10 years. It does seem out of place given the U.S. propensity to "kick the can down the road" to prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Richard Kadziewicz&lt;/b&gt;, Scarborough&lt;/p&gt;
</text></news-item>